<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>patterns on Don B. Stringham</title><link>https://donbstringham.com/tags/patterns/</link><description>Recent content in patterns on Don B. Stringham</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 22:47:30 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://donbstringham.com/tags/patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Service Locator vs. Dependency Injection Container</title><link>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2014-12-23-service-locator-vs-dependency-injection-container/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 22:47:30 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2014-12-23-service-locator-vs-dependency-injection-container/</guid><description>I am NOT as crazy as I thought!
Over the last few years of learning to incorporate Java-like patterns into my PHP development practices one area seemed to drive me crazy, almost to the point of second guessing myself about dependency injection altogether. Years ago I learned from Misko Hevery from Google that a service locator is really just global state or a bad singleton in sheep&amp;rsquo;s clothing. He states that a service locator violates the Law of Demeter and calls singletons are pathological liars.</description></item><item><title>DDD in PHP Experiment</title><link>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2014-12-11-ddd-in-php-experiment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 12:52:29 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2014-12-11-ddd-in-php-experiment/</guid><description>Domain-Driven Design in PHP Experiment and Project Seed
A current and difficult software development project has recently sent me scurrying for answers. In that search I&amp;rsquo;ve rediscovered the book Domain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of Software by Eric Evans. In addition to re-reading the book and reviewing a handful of slide-decks at SlideShare; I have found that there a few different and even wide varying implementations of the principles of domain-driven design.</description></item></channel></rss>