<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code on Don B. Stringham</title>
    <link>https://donbstringham.com/categories/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code on Don B. Stringham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 11:10:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://donbstringham.com/categories/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code Climate</title>
      <link>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2015-05-21-code-climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 11:10:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2015-05-21-code-climate/</guid>
      <description>Make your code NOT suck!
I love the idea of automated code reviews! It makes the development process much faster and allows the engineer to focus more on the business logic. Which is where his attention should be focused. Of the few automated code reviews tools I&amp;rsquo;ve used my favorite is Code Climate. There is only one problem I have with Code Climate and that is it&amp;rsquo;s pricing structure. It is definitely going after the development team or enterprise team audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Programming Mode</title>
      <link>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2015-04-23-different-programming-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:10:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donbstringham.com/posts/2015-04-23-different-programming-modes/</guid>
      <description>Programming is more than just writing code
Many people, including developers, believe that the activity of programming is just writing code. They are either ignorant because they don&amp;rsquo;t develop or do not pay attention while they develop. Programming can be divided into a few activities that have very different mind-sets and this isn&amp;rsquo;t just my experience it also accords with Martin Fowler.
The most popular activity is adding new features. It is the one that most people relate to as the only activity of software development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
